This intermediate Pilates exercise is called the double straight leg stretch, and this is the fourth exercise; part of the five ab series in Pilates, so we really are going to focus really on those abdominal muscles.
So, some on down, lengthen your legs straight up.
Your head and shoulders are lifted off the mat.
Place your hands gently behind your head.
Try not to pull on your neck.
And your legs are in a Pilates stance, meaning that your heels are together, and your toes are out like a V; pointing your toes.
Squeeze your inner thighs.
As you lower your legs down, inhale, and then exhale as you lift your legs back up.
Now, your focus here is to keep the lower back pressing to the mat.
Inhale as you lower, and exhale as you come up.
If you have back issues and you want to modify this exercise, you can place your hands right up up up underneath your hips, and lower your legs down and lift up.
And you want to think about placing the lower part of your head onto the mat. And you want to perform that exercise anywhere between eight to ten reps. That is the double straight leg stretch.